Yah! Left high, left low.
Right low, lunge right.
You break anything, the Septa will have my head.
What is...
Your sister knew perfectly well we were to leave today.
- How she could forget... - She didn't forget.
She's with her dancing master. She's with him every morning.
She always comes back with scrapes and bruises. She's so clumsy.
Hush!
Go back to your room.
Bar the doors.
And do not open them for anyone you do not know.
- What is it? What's happening? - Do as I told you.
Run!
This way!
Left, right.
Now you are dead.
You said right,
but you went left.
And now you are a dead girl.
Only 'cause you lied.
My tongue lied.
My eyes shouted the truth. You were not seeing.
I was so. I watched, but you...
Watching is not seeing, dead girl.
The seeing, the true seeing,
that is the heart of swordplay.
Arya Stark, come with us.
Your father wants to see you.
And why is it that Lord Eddard is sending Lannister men
in place of his own? I am wondering.
Mind your place, dancing master.
This is no concern of yours.
My father wouldn't send you.
And I don't have to go with you if I don't want.
Take her.
Are you men or snakes, that you would threaten a child?
Get out of my way, little man.
I am Syrio Forel...
Foreign bastard.
and you will be speaking to me with more respect.
Kill the Braavosi. Bring the girl.
Arya child, we are done with dancing for the day.
Run to your father.
Bloody oafs.
Be gone now, Arya.
Come with me. Run.
The first sword of Braavos does not run.
What do we say to the god of death?
Not today.
Go.
Not today. Not today.
Stay away from me.
I'll tell my father.
I'll... I'll tell the queen.
Who do you think sent me?
Needle.
There she is.
- What do you want? - I want you, wolf girl.
- Come here. - Leave me be.
My father's a lord. He'll reward you.
She'll reward me... the queen!
Stay away!
Lord Stark, you must be thirsty.
Varys.
I promise you it isn't poisoned.
Why is it no one ever trusts the eunuch?
Not so much, my lord.
I would save the rest, if I were you.
Hide it. Men have been known to die of thirst in these cells.
What about my daughters?
The younger one seems to have escaped the castle.
Even my little birds cannot find her.
- And Sansa? - Still engaged to Joffrey.
Cersei will keep her close.
The rest of your household though... all dead,
it grieves me to say.
I do so hate the sight of blood.
You watched my men being slaughtered and did nothing.
And would again, my lord.
I was unarmed, unarmored
and surrounded by Lannister swords.
When you look at me do you see a hero?
What madness led you to tell the queen
you had learned the truth about Joffrey's birth?
The madness of mercy.
That she might save her children.
Ah, the children.
It is always the innocents who suffer.
It wasn't the wine that killed Robert, nor the boar.
The wine slowed him down and the boar ripped him open,
But it was your mercy that killed the king.
I trust you know you are a dead man, Lord Eddard?
The queen can't kill me.
Cat holds her brother.
The wrong brother sadly.
And lost to her.
Your wife has let the Imp slip through her fingers.
If that's true,
then slit my throat and be done with it.
Not today, my lord.
Tell me something, Varys.
Who do you truly serve?
The realm, my lord.
Someone must.
It's Othor, without a doubt.
The other one is Jafer Flowers, my lord,
Less the hand the wolf tore off.
Any sign of Benjen or the rest of his party?
Just these two, my lord.
Been dead awhile, I'd say.
The smell.
What smell?
There is none.
If they'd be dead for a long time, wouldn't there be rot?
We should burn them.
Snow's not wrong, my lord. Fire will do for them.
The wildling way.
I want Maester Aemon to examine them first.
You may be a coward, Tarly,
but you're not stupid.
- Get them inside. - You heard him.
Lord Commander,
Maester Aemon awaits you in his chambers...
A raven from King's Landing.
Come on, move 'em out.
Bring me a horn of ale, Snow,
and pour one for yourself.
The king is dead.
Is there any word of my father?
Sit.
Lord Stark has been charged with treason.
They say he conspired with Robert's brothers
to deny the throne to Prince Joffrey.
I hope you're not thinking of doing anything stupid.
Your duty lies here now.
My sisters were in King's Landing too.
I'm sure they'll be
treated gently.
Your father has proved to be an awful traitor, dear.
King Robert's body was still warm
when Lord Eddard began
plotting to steal Joffrey's rightful throne.
He wouldn't do that.
He knows how much I love Joffrey. He wouldn't.
Please, your grace, there's been a mistake.
Send for my father. He'll tell you...
the king was his friend.
Sansa sweetling, you are innocent of any wrong. We know that.
Yet you are the daughter of a traitor.
How can I allow you to marry my son?
A child born of a traitor's seed
is no fit consort for our king.
She is a sweet thing now, your grace,
but in 10 years who knows
what treasons she may hatch?
No, I'm not. I'll be a good wife to him, you'll see.
I'll be a queen just like you, I promise.
I won't hatch anything.
The girl is innocent, your grace.
She should be given a chance to prove her loyalty.
Little dove, you must write to Lady Catelyn
and your brother, the eldest, what's his name?
Robb.
Word of your father's arrest will reach him soon, no doubt.
Best it comes from you.
If you would help your father,
urge your brother to keep the king's peace.
Tell him to come to King's Landing
and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
If... if I could see my father, talk to him about...
You disappoint me, child.
We have told you of your father's treason.
Why would you want to speak to a traitor?
I only meant that...
What will happen to him?
- That depends. - On... on what?
On your brother.
And on you.
Treason?
Sansa wrote this?
It is your sister's hand, but the queen's words.
You are summoned to King's Landing
to swear fealty to the new king.
Joffrey puts my father in chains, now he wants his ass kissed?
This is a royal command, my lord.
- If you should refuse to obey... - I won't refuse.
His grace summons me to King's Landing,
I'll go to King's Landing.
But not alone.
Call the banners.
All of them, my lord?
They've all sworn to defend my father, have they not?
They have.
Now we see what their words are worth.
Are you afraid?
I must be.
Good.
Why is that good?
It means you're not stupid.
You've had this since dawn?
He sent it to me, not you.
I've only shown it to you as a courtesy.
A courtesy?!
My husband has been taken prisoner.
My son intends to declare war.
A war?
Your son against the Lannisters?
You should go to him. Teach him patience.
Ned rots in a dungeon and you speak of patience?
He is your brother by law!
Does family mean nothing to you?
Family means everything to me.
And I will not risk Robin's life
to get caught up in another of your husband's wars.
- I'm hungry. - Hush now, darling.
You just ate.
You will not support us then?
Do I understand you correctly?
- But I'm hungry! - Soon, love, soon.
You're always welcome here, sister.
But if you're asking me to send men from the Vale to fight...
That is what I ask.
Go on, sweet. Time for your bath.
I'll feed you after.
If you fear for the safety of your son...
Of course I fear for the safety of my son!
Are you an idiot?
They killed my husband.
You say they shoved your boy from a window.
These people will do anything.
And that is why we have to stop them.
The knights of the Vale will stay in the Vale where they belong,
to protect their lord.
Will you shut up?
There's hill tribes all around here.
If I'm going to die,
it may as well be with a song in my heart.
I should just take your food and leave you here.
What would you do then?
Starve, most likely.
You don't think I'd do it, do you?
What do you want, Bronn? Gold? Women?
Golden women?
Stick with me and you'll have them all,
for as long as I'm around and not for a moment longer.
But you knew that.
That is why you so valiantly took up arms to defend my honor.
Fair enough.
But don't go looking for me to bend the knee
and "My lord" you every time you take a shit.
I'm not your toady and I'm not your friend.
Though I would treasure your friendship,
I'm mainly interested in your facility with murder.
And if the day ever comes when you're tempted to sell me out,
remember this:
whatever their price, I'll beat it.
I like living.
Tyrion.
Come, share our fire.
Help yourselves to our goat.
When you meet your gods, you tell them
Shagga son of Dolf
of the Stone Crows sent you.
I am Tyrion son of Tywin of Clan Lannister.
How would you like to die, Tyrion son of Tywin?
In my own bed, at the age of 80
with a bellyful of wine and a girl's mouth around my cock.
Take the half man.
He can dance for the children. Kill the other one.
No no no no no!
My... my house is rich and powerful.
If you see us through these mountains,
my father will shower you with gold.
We have no use for a half man's promises.
Half a man maybe,
but at least I have the courage to face my enemies.
What do the Stone Crows do?
Hide behind rocks and shiver
when the knights of the Vale ride by?
Are those the best weapons you could steal?
Good enough for killing sheep,
if the sheep don't fight back.
Lannister smiths shit better steel.
You think you can win us over with your trinkets?
That trinket is worth more than everything your tribe owns.
But if you help us, Shagga son of Dolf,
I will not give you trinkets.
I will give you this.
What is "This"?
The Vale of Arryn.
The lords of the Vale have always spat upon the hill tribes.
The lords of the Vale want me dead.
I believe it is time for new lords of the Vale.
Now there's a rare sight...
not only a bastard, but a traitor's bastard.
- Jon, no! - Jon, stop, put it down!
Blood will always tell.
You'll hang for this, bastard.
I told you not to do anything stupid.
You're confined to quarters. Go.
Ghost, what's wrong?
Is something out there?
Commander?
Stay.
Hello?
Who's there?
Lord commander?
Snow?
Commander!
Move move!
What did they do?
I thought the Dothraki didn't believe in money.
Gold to hire ships, princess,
ships to sail to Westeros.
Jorah, make them stop.
- Khaleesi? - You heard me.
These men have shed blood for their khal.
Now they claim their rewards.
Princess, you have a gentle heart,
but this is how it's always been.
I do not have a gentle heart, ser.
Kash qoy qoyi thira disse. Me qorasokh anni!
- Come. - Anha afichak mae m'arakhoon!
What do you want done with them?
Bring her to me. And those women there.
You cannot claim them all, princess.
I can,
and I will.
Me fati!
Khaleesi vazha anhaan qorasokh anni,
Ch'anha afichak mae m'arakhoon anni!
Me vastoe hatif anni;
Ahhazaan yer nemo vacchaki.
Ohos.
Os.
Thank you, Silver Lady.
Who are you?
I am named Mirri Maz Duur.
I was the godswife of this temple.
My mother was godswife here before me.
She taught me how to make healing smokes and ointments.
All men are of one flock, so my people believe.
The Great Shepherd sent me to earth to heal his...
lamb or lion,
his wound must be washed and sewn
or it will fester.
For 30 years I've been making corpses
out of men, boy.
I'm the man you want leading the vanguard.
Galbart Glover will lead the van.
The bloody wall will melt
before an Umber marches behind a Glover.
I will lead the van
or I will take my men and march them home.
You are welcome to do so, Lord Umber.
And when I am done with the Lannisters
I will march back north,
root you out of your keep
and hang you for an oathbreaker.
Oathbreaker, is it?!
I'll not sit here and swallow insults
from a boy so green he pisses grass.
My lord father taught me
it was death to bare steel against your liege lord.
But doubtless the Greatjon only meant to cut my meat for me.
Your meat...
is bloody tough.
- What is it? What's happened? - Shh, it's all right.
- Where are you going? - South. For father.
But it's the middle of the night.
The Lannisters have spies everywhere.
I don't want them to know we're coming.
They have more men than we do.
Aye, they do.
Can't I come with you?
I can ride now. You've seen me riding.
And I won't get in the way, I...
There must always be a Stark at Winterfell.
Until I return that will be you.
You are not to leave the castle walls while we are gone.
Do you understand?
Listen to Maester Luwin. Look after your little brother.
I will.
I'll send letters whenever I can,
but if you don't hear from me,
don't be scared.
Until I return.
How long have you been hiding outhere?
Robb will be looking for you to say goodbye.
They've all gone away.
They'll be back soon. Robb will free father
and they'll come back with mother.
No, they won't.
Please watch over Robb.
And watch over all the other men from Winterfell.
And Theon too, I suppose.
You hear them, boy?
The old gods are answering you.
What are you doing here?
They're my gods too.
Beyond the Wall, they're the only gods.
Even slaves are allowed to pray.
You're not a slave.
Well, your friend did put a knife to my roat.
I'm not complaining, little lord,
Just telling truths.
What did you mean about hearing the gods?
You asked them,
they're answering you.
Open your ears.
It's only the wind.
Who do you think sends the wind
if not the gods?
They see you, boy.
They hear you.
Your brother will get no help from them where he's going.
The old gods have no power in the south.
The weirwoods there were all cut down a long time ago.
How can they watch when they have no eyes?
Well, there's a big man.
He has giants' blood in him or I'm the queen.
Go back and find your clothes, Hodor.
Go dress.
Hodor.
Are there really giants beyond the Wall?
Giants and worse than giants.
I tried telling your brother,
he's marching the wrong way.
All these swords, they should be going north, boy.
North, not south!
The cold winds are rising.
They were touched by white walkers.
That's why they came back.
That's why their eyes turned blue.
Only fire will stop them.
How do you know that?
I read about it in a book...
a very old book in Maester Aemon's library.
What else did the book say?
The white walkers
sleep beneath the ice for thousands of years.
And when they wake up...
And when they wake up, what?
I hope the Wall is high enough.
Summer snows, my lady.
Robb's brought the north with him.
The River Lords are falling back
with Jaime Lannister at their heels.
And Lord Tywin is bringing
around a second Lannister army from the south.
Our scouts confirm it's even larger than The Kingslayer's.
One army or two, the kings in the North
threw back hosts 10 times as large.
Mother!
You look well.
Lady Catelyn, you're a welcome sight
in these troubled times.
We had not thought to meet you here, my lady.
I had not thought to be here.
I would speak with my son alone.
I know you will forgive me, my lords.
You heard her! Move your asses!
Come on, out.
You too, Greyjoy. Are you bloody deaf?
Have no fear, my lady.
We'll shove our swords up Tywin Lannister's bunghole
and then it's on to the Red Keep to free Ned.
- You old devil, Rodrik. - Jon.
You're not wasting away, are you?
I remember the day you came into this world
red-faced and squalling.
And now I find you leading a host to war.
- There was no one else. - No one?
Who were those men I saw here?
- None of them are Starks. - All of them are seasoned in battle.
If you think you can send me back to Winterfell...
Oh, would that I could.
There was a letter.
From Sansa.
From the queen, you mean.
- There's no mention of Arya. - No.
How many men do you have?
18,000.
If I go to King's Landing and bend my knee to Joffrey...
You would never be allowed to leave. No.
Our best hope... our only hope...
is that you can defeat them in the field.
And if I lose?
Do you know what happened to the Targaryen children
- when the Mad King fell? - They were butchered in their sleep.
On the orders of Tywin Lannister.
And the years have not made him kinder.
If you lose,
your father dies,
your sisters die,
we die.
Well, that makes it simple then.
I suppose it does.
From here it might be best if Bronn and I continue alone.
Best for Tyrion son of Tywin.
Not best for me.
If the half man betrays us,
Shagga son of Dolf will cut off his manhood...
And feed it to the goats, yes.
All right then.
Time to meet my father.
- Tyrion. - Uncle.
Father.
The rumors of your demise were unfounded.
Sorry to disappoint you.
And who are these...
companions of yours?
This is Shagga son of Dolf,
Chieftain of the Stone Crows.
Timett son of Timett, ruler of the Burned Men.
This fair maid is Chella daughter of Cheyk,
leader of the Black Ears.
And here we have Bronn son of...
You wouldn't know him.
May I present my lord father,
Tywin son of Tytos of house Lannister,
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the west.
Kind of you to go to war for me.
You left us no choice.
The honor of the house was at stake.
Your brother would never have submitted to capture so meekly.
We have our differences, Jaime and I.
He's braver. I'm better looking.
He's been covering himself in glory.
Jaime smashed the River Lords at the Golden Tooth,
and now lays siege to Riverrun,
Catelyn Stark's homeland.
And the Starks? Lord Eddard?
Is our hostage. He will lead no armies from his dungeon cell.
How did my sweet sister persuade the king
to imprison his dear friend Ned?
Robert Baratheon is dead.
Joffrey rules in King's Landing.
My sister rules, you mean.
Stark's son has called his banners.
- He moves south with a strong host. - A green boy.
One taste of battle and he'll run back to Winterfell
with his tail between his legs.
Maybe.
Though the boy does have a certain belligerence.
You'd like him.
While we're on the subject of war,
I made promises to my friends here
and a Lannister always pays his debts.
We shall require 3,000 helms and shields,
plus swords, pikes,
gorgets, maces...
If it please my lord,
Ser Addam bids me report that
the northmen have crossed the Neck.
The wolf rushes into the lion's jaws.
So be it. Kevan, command the drummers beat assembly.
And send word to Jaime
that I am moving against Robb Stark.
At once, my lord.
It is said that the men of the mountain clans are great warriors.
Ride with me against my enemies
and you shall have all my son promised you and more.
Only if the half man fights with us.
Until we hold the steel he pledged us,
the little lion's life is ours.
The scouts report Lord Tywin moves north.
We need to get him on broken ground,
put his knights at a disadvantage.
No, we need to get around him
and break Jaime Lannister's siege of Riverrun.
Do that and the River Lords will join us.
To do either we need to cross the river
and the only crossing is at the Twins.
Lord Frey controls that bridge.
Your father's bannerman.
"The late Lord Frey" My father calls him.
At the Trident, he didn't appear until the battle was done.
Some men takes their oaths more seriously than others.
Robb's right. We need that bridge.
So what's it going to be?
Do we move against Jaime or lord Tywin?
Your pardon, my lords.
We've captured a Lannister scout.
Don't worry, lad. He won't be leaving this tent with his head.
Where did you find him?
In the brush above the encampment.
He looked to be counting.
How high did you get?
20,000. Maybe more.
You don't have to do this yourself.
Your father would understand...
My father unrstands mercy, when there is room for it.
And he understands honor...
and courage.
Let him go.
Robb.
Tell lord Tywin winter is coming for him.
20,000 northerners marching south
to find out if he really does shit gold.
Yes, my lord.
Thank you, my lord.
Are you touched, boy?! Letting him go?
You call me boy again.
Go on.
It is also the wish of his grace
that his loyal servant Janos Slynt,
- Commander of the city watch... - Ser Aron.
be at once raised to the rank of lord...
- Lord Gyles. - ...And granted the ancient seat of Harrenhal,
and that his sons and grandsons shall hold this honor
after him until the end of time.
In the place of the traitor Eddard Stark,
it is the wish of his grace that Tywin Lannister,
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the West,
be appointed Hand of the king.
Lastly, in these times of treason and turmoil,
it is the view of the council
that the life and safety
of King Joffrey
be of paramount importance.
Ser Barristan Selmy.
Your grace, I am yours to command.
Rise, ser Barristan.
You may remove your helm.
You have served the realm long and faithfully.
Every man and woman in the Seven Kingdoms owes you thanks.
But it is time to put aside your armor and your sword.
It is time to rest and look back with pride
on your many years of service.
Your grace, the kingsguard is a sworn brotherhood.
Our vows are taken for life.
Only death relieves us of our sacred trust.
Whose death, ser Barristan? Yours or your king's?
You let my father die.
You're too old to protect anybody.
- Your grace... - The council has determined
that ser Jaime Lannister will take your place
as lord commander of the kingsguard.
The man who profaned his blade
with the blood of the king he had sworn to defend!
Careful, Ser.
We have nothing but gratitude
for your long service, good ser.
You shall be given a stout keep beside the sea,
with servants to look after your every need.
A hall to die in
and men to bury me.
I am a knight.
I shall die a knight.
A naked knight, apparently.
Even now I could cut through the five of you like carving a cake!
Here, boy!
Melt it down and add it to the others.
If any man in this hall has other matters
to set before his grace, let him speak now
or go forth and hold his silence.
Your grace.
Come forward, my lady.
The lady Sansa of house Stark.
Do you have some business for the king and the council, Sansa?
I do.
As it please your grace, I ask mercy for my father,
Lord Eddard Stark, who was Hand of the king.
Treason is a noxious weed.
- It should be torn out, root... - Let her speak.
I want to hear what she says.
Thank you, your grace.
Do you deny your father's crime?
No, my lords. I know he must be punished.
All I ask is mercy.
I know my lord father must regret what he did.
He was King Robert's friend and he loved him.
You all know he loved him.
He never wanted to be Hand until the king asked him.
They must have lied to him... lord Renly or lord Stannis
or somebody. They must have lied!
He said I wasn't the king.
Why did he say that?
He was badly hurt.
Maester Pycelle was giving him milk of the poppy.
He wasn't himself. Otherwise he never would have said it.
A child's faith... Such sweet innocence.
And yet they say wisdom oft comes
from the mouths of babes.
Treason is treason!
Anything else?
If you still have any affection in your heart for me,
please do me this kindness, your grace.
Your sweet words have moved me.
But your father has to confess.
He has to confess and say that I'm the king...
or there'll be no mercy for him.
He will.